(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-02T21:52:22.643382",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
みんなー！
Everyone—!
こんばんはー！
Good evening!
わっしょい！わっしょい！わっしょい！わっしょい！
Wasshoi! Wasshoi! Wasshoi! Wasshoi!
すげえBGMめっちゃデカくない？
Isn't the BGM super loud?
そんな！
No way!
皆さんこんばんは！お元気でございましたか？
Good evening everyone! How have you all been?
はい、ホロライブの青春担当とみんなのアイドル夏色まつりです！
Yes, I'm Hololive's youth representative and everyone's idol, Natsuiro Matsuri!
みんな！よっほー！よっほー！わっしょい！
Everyone! Yoho! Yoho! Wasshoi!
こんばんわっしょい！よっほー！
Konba-wasshoi! Yoho!
と言うことでね、えー今日は何のひか？
So, um, what day is it today, everyone?
皆さん、知っておりますでしょうか？BGMでかくないやっぱり？
Do you all know? Isn't the BGM too loud?
めちゃでかいよね？ごめんよ。
Super loud, right? Sorry about that.
知ってましたかね？
Did you know?
はい、はい、はい、はい。
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
こんばんは！今日はですね、えー、下駄の日
Good evening! Today is, um, Geta Day,
夏の日、円周率金日時の日って書いてあるけど、なになに、ナイス？
Summer Day, Pi Gold Date and Time Day, wait, what, nice?
なんだそれは。知らない、知らないんだけど、円周率金日時の日って何ですか？
What is that? I don't know, but what is Pi Gold Date and Time Day?
いやいやいや、今日はですね、その我らがホロライブの夏色まつりの誕生日では、ないですか皆さん！
No no no, today is, isn't it the birthday of none other than our Hololive's Natsuiro Matsuri, everyone!
ね、誕生日でございます！
Right, it is my birthday!
ということでね、こちらに上に準備してあるのでね、まつりがえいって言ったら割れるそうなのでね
And since it's prepared up here, when Matsuri says "Ei!", it'll break,
ちょっとみんなで割っていきましょうか。いきますよ。
so let's all break it together. Here we go.
せーの、えい！どーん！わー！割れた！
Ready, go! Ei! Boom! Wow! It broke!
エビフライオンが、エビフライオンがめっちゃ、めっちゃんこ
The Ebi-Fry-on, the Ebi-Fry-on is super, super...
そしてなんか下から出てきましたよ。お、これはめっちゃ豪華年ぶりに出てきた。
And something came out from below. Oh, this came out after ages.
ちょっと待って、エビフライオンで過ぎて分か、あ、出てきた出てきた！
Wait, there are too Ebi-Fry-ons-- ah, it came out, it came out!
これ豪華年ぶりに見た。
I haven't seen this in ages.
これね、あのまつりの、あの、配信でね、あのスーパーチャットをしてくださるとね、あの出てくるやつ、やつでございます。
This is, um, the thing that pops up when you send a super chat on Matsuri's stream.
はい、ありがとうございます！
Yes, thank you very much!
そしてね、後ろはなんかすげえ額を投げた人ですね。すげえ額を投げた人がね、
And behind me are the people who threw a crazy amount [of money]. The people who threw a crazy amount
あの、出てきます。ありがとうございます本当に！
will appear. Thank you so much, really!
たくさんの人にね祝ってもらえてね、あの昨日、昨日っていうか夜もね、
So many people celebrated with me, um, yesterday-- well, yesterday meaning last night,
あのカウントダウン配信をしたんですけど、もう本当にすごくってね、
I did a countdown stream, and it was really amazing,
もうまつりはびっくりして、おりましたけども、ありがとうございます本当に。
and Matsuri was so surprised, but thank you so much, really.
おめでとうございますね。
Congratulations to me.
と言うことでみなさんね、あとこちら出ておりますけど、夏色まつり誕生祭3Dでですね、ハッシュタグツイートいっぱいしてくださいね、お願います！
And so everyone, also, this is displayed here, Natsuiro Matsuri Birthday Festival 3D, please tweet a lot with the hashtag, please!
誕生日おめでとうって、みんなありがとうございます！本当に、本当にたくさんの人が来てくださってる、ありがとうございます！
Happy birthday, thank you everyone! Really, really so many people came, thank you so much!
はい、ということで前回はね、先月か活動2周年のね、ライブを
Yes, so last time, last month, I did my 2nd anniversary live,
やらせていただいて、今日はねまつりのことをね、まあ前回はライブだったからね、
and today, about Matsuri, well, since last time was a live concert,
あんまりあれだった、なんかこうじっくり見るかっていう感じではなくね、わあ、ライブだ！すげえ！っていう感じだったと思うのでね、
it wasn't really a feeling of looking at things slowly, but rather "Wow, a live! Amazing!",
今回は久しぶりに撮影会なるものをしていきたいと思います！おめでとう！
so this time, I want to do something like a photo shoot session for the first time in a while! Congratulations!
ということでね、えーと夏色まつりの3Dお披露目みんないつか覚えてる？まあ最近知った人はね、あんまりわかんないと思うんだけど、2019年の4月15日だったですね。
And so, um, does everyone remember when Natsuiro Matsuri's 3D reveal was? Well, people who learned about me recently might not know, but it was April 15, 2019.
懐かしいな。
It's been a while, huh?
懐かしい、この体を手にいれてからもう1年以上が経つんですね。
It's been over a year since I got this body.
というわけで、久しぶりにこの教室にも来たということで、パシャパシャと撮影会をしていきましょうか！
So, let's take some photos with everyone!
はい。
Yeah!
じゃあ、どこから撮ろうかな。とりあえずちょっとアップで撮っちゃおうかな？かわいく。
Let's take them close-up for now, nice and cute.
かわいく撮ってもらって、アップで、ちょっとカメラさん寄ってもらっていいですか？
Can you get nice and close for me?
あ、なんか、ピース。
Ah, let's see... peace sign!
どうですか？可愛い？
How's that? Cute?
あの、このね、あの、可愛い顔はこのハッシュタグつけてTwitterでつぶやいてね！
And post this cute face on Twitter with the hashtag!
彗星のごとく現れた、はーちゃまー！
Appearing like starlight, it's Haachama!
これ、これめっちゃ好きなんだよね、このポーズ。
I really love this pose.
めちゃ可愛い？あら、ありがとう！
So cute! Oh, thank you!
ありがとう。ちょっと後ろの人と撮れるよ、これ。
Thank you. Can I take a photo with the person behind me?
ででー！
Tee-hee!
撮れる？
Can we?
可愛い、ありがとうございます！
So cute, thank you very much!
ありがとう。
Thank you!
ガチ恋距離ってやつだよ。
This is the "Gachi-koi distance" style, you know?
どう？こんなに近づくことあんまないでしょ、3Dで。
You don't usually get this close in 3D!
ピース！ピース！
Peace! Peace!
なんかさ、最近のさ、若者の、若者ってまっ高校生だけどさ、
Lately, you know, the youth... well, they're high school students though.
若者のさ、ハート、編みて？ぎゅんべす！
Young people's heart symbol... have you seen it? Gyum!
ぎゅんば、ぎゅんば、ぎゅん！ぎゅん！可愛い！
Gyum, gyum, gyum! Gyum, cute!
可愛いすぎる。顔が大きい？は？
Too cute! Is my face big? Huh?
顔大きくないよ。
My face isn't big!
ほかに、ほかにどんなポーズがいいとかありますか？
Are there any other good poses?
あ、でも待って、あれやりたい！
Oh, wait, I want to do that one!
えっとね、なんだったっけ？船長のやつ。えっと、なんたらかんたらかんたら、なんたらかんたら、船長の宝箱マリンです！
What is it called again? The captain's treasure... no, Marin's!
なんて言うんだっけあれ？忘れちゃった。
What's it called again? I forgot!
船長のやつめっちゃやりたかった！
I really wanted to do the captain's pose.
あ、るしあも来てくれてる！
Oh, Lucia came to see us too!
さっきね、メルメルとね、ここちも見たんですけど、ありがとうございます！
Earlier I saw Mel-meru and Coco too, thank you!
そしてパパも来てくれてる。ありがとう！ありがとうございまーす！
And Papa came too. Thank you!
ここちゃん可愛い、若い！
Coco-chan is so cute, so young!
動きが。船長のポーズ。
Her movements... The captain's pose.
なんだろうな、あの深さなのかな、あの、なんだろう、年齢感は、年齢感はこっちかな？
What is it, like... depth? You know, the age gap.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
なんかこう、指示をくださったらね、指示をくださったら、あまつさローアンでさ、撮りたいんだよ、ローアンで。ローアンしてください。
If you give me instructions, I want to take it in low-angle, please!
ローアン。
Low-angle.
どう、こういうの。おりゃだ！おりゃだ、お前！
How's this? Take that, you jerk!
私タイツだから恥ずかしくないからさ、
I'm wearing tights, so it's not embarrassing.
なんでもできちゃ、ちょっと、
I can do anything.
上げすぎじゃない？ちょっとカメラさん！
Wait, that's too high! Wait, the camera...
あ、そうそうそうそうそう、そのへん、そのへんそれ。おりゃ、おりゃだ。おりゃ、おりゃ、おりゃ、おりゃ。
Ah, right, right, right, around there. There, there. Take it, take it!
可愛い。ありがとう、ありがとうございます。
So cute! Thank you, thank you very much.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
タイツだから恥ずかしくないもん。
I'm wearing tights so I'm not embarrassed.
なんでもできちゃうもん。
I can do anything.
え、じゃないよ、全然。
Not at all!
可愛いんでしょ？
I'm cute, right?
ね、やっぱね、顔がいいんですよね。
Well, you know, the face is the best part.
あ、ちょっと待って。ちょっと！
Oh, wait, hold on. Hey!
ちょっと、カメラマンさん！カメラマンさん、今祭の胸を映したね？
Hey, cameraman! Cameraman, you just filmed Matsuri's chest, didn't you?
ちょっと。
Hey!
ちょっと、そんな祭のタワーのこの胸が見たいからって、だめ、だめだぞ！だめだぞ、お前！
You can't just say you want to see Matsuri's tower of a chest! No way, idiot!
うーん、もうこんな大きなおっぱいを見せてしまって、すみませんね、ちょっとYouTubeくん、大丈夫ですか？
I'm sorry for showing you such big breasts! YouTube-kun, are you okay?
今度誕生日だから許してください、お願いします。
It's my birthday, so please forgive me, I beg you.
壁しか見えないって言ったやつ、マジで後で、後でお前、マジで覚えとけよ！
I'll really remember this later, saying only the walls are visible!
あとね、久しぶりにさ、Yバランスやりたいなって思って、思ったんすよ。
Also, you know, I wanted to do the Y-balance for a long time... I thought.
でもたぶん、もうできないんだよね。
But I probably can't do it anymore, right?
しばらくやってなさすぎて、固く、この、股がさ、固くなってるからさ、
I've been sitting for too long and my thighs are stiff!
できるかな？あ、ちょ、足りん、ちょ、足りてない？
Can I do it? Ah, a little short.
ちょっと足りてないけどギリ？ギリセーフ？ギリセーフですか？
Is it barely safe? Barely safe?
昔やつ、もっと上手できた気がするんだけど、今できない。
The old one... I feel like I did it better before, but I can't do it now.
だいぶ固くなってしまった。
It's gotten so stiff.
すごい？ありがとう。
Is that amazing? Thank you.
なんか膝が曲がってたけど、ま、セーフでしょ。K！
My knees were bent, but it's safe, right? K!
Kのポーズ！ピン！
K pose! Pin!
うまくできなかったわ。
I couldn't do it well.
まだできて る？
Can I still do it?
あとでもね、これはね、これ、やると怒られる？
Also, you know, this... if I do this, I'll get yelled at.
これ、これ、ちょっとやめていただきたいって言われたんでやりますね。ちょっとだめだって。
They told me to stop doing that, so I'll stop.  It's no good,
ちょっと、さすがにアイドルとしてだめだったわ。
As an idol, that was no good.
立ては？立てはいいですか？
How about standing? Is standing okay?
あ、あ、あ、だめだって。だめだって。
Ah, ah, ah, it's no good. It's no good.
じゃあ座るんで。
Well, since I'm sitting down...
座ってるんで、ちょっと下のほうから映してもらっていいですか？
...could you film me from a bit lower down?
ダメだって。やっぱおまたが見えるやつあんまよくないんだよね。
No way. It's not good if your crotch shows.
アイドルになったもんだね。
I guess I've really become an idol.
昔はさ、やってたんだよお祭りだって。
Back in the day, Matsuri used to do stuff like that.
え、なんかセクシーじゃない？ちょっと見て！
Hey, isn't this kind of sexy? Take a look!
ちょっと上さ、ちょ、あのカメラの、この辺からこの辺から映して。こっちから。
From a bit above, wait, from around here on the camera, film from here. From this side.
え？どどうどうどう？でなんかセクシーじゃない？
Huh? Ho-how, how, how? Isn't it kind of sexy?
え？どう？ちょわかんない
Huh? How is it? I don't know...
セクシーって何？この感じ？どう？
...what is sexy? This vibe? How?
どうですかこれ？ねえ？これはセクシー？
How's this? Hey? Is this sexy?
いい？セクシー？
Good? Sexy?
セクシーだって！
She said I'm sexy!
やったー！やったねみんな！
Yay! Yay, everyone!
じゃあそろそろ、そろそろ？そろそろですか？そろそろですね。
Well, is it about time? About time? Is it about time? It's about time, then.
あのね、これ台本読んでいいですか？ある程度撮影し終わったら、あ、なるほどなるほど。
Um, can I read the script for this? Once we finish taking photos to a certain extent... Ah, I see, I see.
じゃあそろそろね、次のこと
Then, it's about time we...
やっていこうかなと思います。みんな撮れた？
...move on to the next thing. Did everyone take pictures?
あ、撮れたらこれでツイートするんだよ。いい？撮った？可愛く撮った？ありがとう。
If you've taken them, you tweet them with this. Okay? Did you take them? Did you make them look cute? Thank you!
じゃあね、今からですね、まあなんか初心に戻るってのがね今回のねやりたいことなんです。
Well, from now on, uh, returning to our roots is something I want to do this time.
なので今から初心に戻ってジェスチャーゲームでもしましょう！
So, going back to our roots, let's play a game of charades!
なんか、最近ジェスチャーゲームってさ、減ってきてない？なんか減ってきてる気がするんだよね。
Lately, aren't charades games sort of disappearing? I feel like they've been on the decline.
まあ初心も初心ですよ。まつりちゃんは、まあ前回の誕生日とかもやった気がするんですけど、はい、ジェスチャーゲームをやっていきたいと思います。
Well, this is going right back to the roots. I feel like Matsuri-chan did this around my last birthday and stuff, but yes, I'd like to do some charades.
え、みんなが一杯コメントで答えてください。まつりが動きます。正解してくださいね。
Um, everyone, please answer lots in the comments. Matsuri will move. Make sure you get it right, okay?
それじゃあまず1問目！あ、時間は大体30秒くらいでいきますので。よーーい、スタート！
Now then, question 1! Ah, time will be about 30 seconds or so. Ready, start!
あ、正解正解！正解が出る正解が出る正解が出る！やったー！正解は、
Ah, correct, correct! Someone got it right, someone got it right, someone got it right! Yay! The answer is...
お化け屋敷
A haunted house.
でしたー！やった！正解正解！すごいすごい！正解だよ！声入ってる？嘘。しゃべってない、しゃべってないよ。
! Yay! Correct, correct! Amazing, amazing! You got it right! Is my voice going through? No way. I wasn't talking, I wasn't talking.
じゃあ次行くよ！次の問題！
Alright, moving on! Next question!
で、えーっと、うんと、あ、シャランラ！ボンジュールのシャランラ！それを見守る
And, um, let's see, ah, sha-la-la! Bon-jour's sha-la-la! Watching over it...
シャランラ！ビーク、ビーク。あ！正解正解！正解が！正解が出る正解が出る正解です！正解は、
Sha-la-la! Beak, beak. Ah! Correct, correct! Someone got— someone got it right, someone got it right, it's correct! The answer is...
エッフェル塔
The Eiffel Tower.
エッフェル塔って何かわかんなくて、聞いた、聞きました。あの東京タワーのヨーロッパバージョンですね。
I didn't know what the Eiffel Tower was, so I asked. It's like the European version of the Tokyo Tower, you see.
で聞きました。正解です。あ、次のお題は声を出してはいけませんって言われました。
I heard about it. That's correct. Ah, for the next topic, I was told I must not make any sounds.
じゃあ次いきます！いくよ！いくよいくよ！いくよ！行きます。次、続いて。
Alright, going next! Here we go! Here we go, here we go! Here we go! Let's go. Next, continuing.
あ、出た！あ、正解正解！正解エペクス！エペクスです！
Ah, it came out! Ah, correct, correct! Correct, Apex! It's Apex!
よかったよかった！よくわかってくれたね。あの待機画面のさ、パスファインダー！
Thank goodness! You understood so well. Pathfinder from that waiting screen!
パスファインダーわかってくれて、オクタンもわかってくれてよかったよ。ありがとうございました。
I'm glad you guys figured out Pathfinder, and Octane too. Thank you very much.
じゃあ続いて、続いてこれ難しくない？じゃあ続いていきますよ。行きます。スタート！
Now, continuing... isn't this next one hard? Well, let's keep going. Here we go. Start!
正解いる、正解いる、正解いる、正解は――
"Got it? Got it? Got it? The answer is..."
友人A（えーちゃん）！
"Friend A (A-chan)!"
表情がわかんなくて、表情がわかんなくて。
"Her expression was hard to show, her expression was hard to show."
これとメガネかけてるよって、この仕草じゃ表現できなくて、
"And I couldn't express wearing glasses with just this gesture,"
胸！おっぱい無いよー！
"Chest! She has no boobs!"
あーー！
"Ahhh!"
うえさんから教えてもらった。これ、これだ！これえーちゃんんだ。
"Ue-san taught me this. This is it! This is A-chan."
確かに、確かに。確かにそれはそうだ。
"True, true. That's totally true."
ごめん、胸のことしか考えてなくて。
"Sorry, I was only thinking about her chest."
ごめんなさい。でもね、正解が出たってことは、
"Sorry. But you know, getting the right answer means..."
胸の表現でだいぶ伝わったっていうことですよ、皆さん。
"my chest gesture got the point across, right everyone?"
そういうことだよね。まあ、悪くないね。笑
"That's how it is. Well, not bad, right? Haha."
じゃあ続いてが最後のお題でございます。これはね、わかると思う。いくよ！
"Now for the final topic. You'll definitely get this. Here we go!"
あ、あ、正解、正解、正解、正解！
"Ah, ah, correct, correct, correct, correct!"
正解は、ルーナ……ねねねねねー
"The answer is Lu... na...neneneneー"
ルーナ……ルーナ、なんだのら！
"Luna... Luna, that's what it is, nora!"
だよねー、そっくり、そっくりだったよ。そっくりだったよ！
"Right? It was just like you, totally just like you!"
なんだのらー、なんだのらー
"What's that, nora~, what's that, nora~"
だこうやって歌ってたじゃん、こうやって、こうやって
"You were singing like this, like this, like this"
おどおどしてたのら、なんだのら、なんだのらー
"You were acting all timid, nora, what's that, nora~"
違う、違うんだよ。違うんだよー
"No, that's not it. That's not it~"
そんな感じだったが、可愛く自己紹介してください。ルーナちゃんどんなんですか？
"Something like that. Please give a cute self-introduction, Luna-chan, what is it like?"
はーいのだ！ぜんそくとせくしータントの、姫森ルーナなのだー！
"Okay nora! The asthmatic and sexy-tant, Himemori Luna nora~!"
はい、ということで今日はいききれてないですか、まだ？まだきれてないの？
"Alright, so today, haven't you caught your breath yet? Still out of breath?"
まだ息切れ……まだ息切れてるのら？息切れてないのらー
"Still out of breath... are you still out of breath, nora? I'm not out of breath~"
ルーナは今日はなん、なんで来てくれたんですか？
"Luna, why did you come here today?"
なんだのら！今日はまつり先輩のお誕生日だから、お祝いをしに、来たに決まってるのらー！
"What's that nora! Today is Matsuri-senpai's birthday, so of course I came to celebrate, nora~!"
ちゃんと、ちゃんとプレゼントも、持ってきたのらー！
"And I brought a proper present too, nora~!"
えっ、本当に？
"Eh, really?"
じゃあ、ちょっとさせてもらってもいいですか？ よし、水がいいなら、せーのー、じゃーん！
"Then, may I do it a little? Alright, if water is good, ready, set, ta-da!"
おー！すげえケーキだ！
"Oh! That's an amazing cake!"
それいー、それいー、それいー……でっか、でかくなってる、でっかくなってるのら！
"Surprise, surprise, surprise... it's getting huge, it's getting huge, nora!"
でかっ！なんだこれ！
"Huge! What is this?!"
この大きいケーキを、持ってきてくれたの？ そうなんだのら。ルーナすごいね、どうやってやったの？これは
"Did you bring this huge cake? That's right, nora. Luna is amazing, how did you do this?"
ルーナの魔法なのだ。こんなのかんたんなのだよ
"It's Luna's magic. This kind of thing is easy."
はい、ということでね、ルーナがケーキを今日は持ってきててくださいました。
"So, Luna brought us a cake today."
そしてですね、こちらバーチャルケーキなんですけど、まあみんなに分かりやすいように、ルーナが持ってきてくれたケーキをお写真で写したいと思います。こちらね！
"And this is a virtual cake, but so everyone can easily see it, we'll show photos of the cake Luna brought. Here it is!"
めっちゃかわいいよ！めちゃめちゃかわいいじゃん！
"It's super cute! It's so cute!"
ケーキの中に入っちゃった。かわいい。めっちゃかわいい。センスあるよね。
"It got inside the cake. Cute. Super cute. You have good taste."
ありがとうございます。
"Thank you very much."
じゃあ早速ちょっと食べに行こうかなと思います。ルーナどっちがいい？
"Then I think we should go eat some right away. Luna, which one do you want?"
まつり先輩が食べたほうがいいのらよ。
"Matsuri-senpai should eat first, nora."
え、両方？あ、フォークが、両方？あ、じゃあ両方、待って待って、はんぶんこしよう。
"Eh, both? Ah, the fork is... both? Ah, then both, wait wait, let's share them half and half."
どっちも、待って、はんぶんこしよう。ちょっと行くよ。
"Both, wait, let's share them. Here we go."
はんぶんこ、はんぶんこ。ぐさ。いっただきまーす
"Half and half, half and half. Stab. Itadakimasu!"
はんぶんこケーキさせない。ぐさ。
"Can't let you share the cake. Stab."
あ、刺さった刺さった！いただきます。食べます。はんぶんこなのだー！
"Ah, it stuck, it stuck! Itadakimasu. I'll eat. It's half and half, nora~!"
はんぶんこなのだー！あ、刺さった。お互いでも刺さっとるわ。美味しい！
"Half and half, nora~! Ah, it stuck. We both stuck it in. Delicious!"
やったー！私たちも食べよう。食べる？
"Yay! Let's eat too. Will you eat?"
どっちも、どっちも食べ、あ、あ、美味しい！
"Let's eat both, both eat—ah, ah, delicious!"
こっちも食べてみよう。この毛虫……
"Let's try eating this too. This caterpillar..."
毛虫じゃなくてテントウムシ！テントウムシ……毛虫じゃねえんだわ。テントウムシだわ。うん、美味しい！
"Not a caterpillar, a ladybug! Ladybug... it's not a caterpillar. It's a ladybug. Mhm, delicious!"
あ、これ、美味しい、チョコレート！
"Ah, this is delicious, chocolate!"
あ、チョコなのだね。よかったのだー！
"Ah, it's chocolate, nora. I'm glad, nora~!"
あーん
Ah...
おいしー
Delicious.
ちゃんとケーキ美味しかった？
Was the cake delicious?
うん
Yeah.
美味しかった？うん美味しかった
Delicious? Yeah, delicious.
じゃああとちょっと配信終わったらさ、うんうん
Well, after the stream ends, yeah...
いい？うんうん。
Ready? Yeah.
じゃあちょっとこれ
Here, take this.
あお水、ありがとうございます！あ
Ah, water, thank you! Ah...
普通に
Normally...
写真ね皆さん、うん
Take a picture, everyone, yeah.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
じゃあちょっとみんなにもさ、二人で食べさせてあげるよ
Now, let's feed everyone too, the two of us.
リスナーの皆さんにもね
To all the listeners too, right.
さして？
Feed them?
持ってないのか？
You don't have one?
かんかん！じゃあ祭りが食べさせてあげますまず
Kan-kan! Well, Matsuri will feed you first.
はーい、みんな！あーーー！あーーー！みんな食べるのだな！
Hi everyone! Ahhhh! Ahhhh! Everyone eat up!
はい、もっと食べて！
Yes, eat more!
もっと食べて！
Eat more!
でかい！
Huge!
はいフォークも食べて！はい！はい！ぱく！フォークあげる
Yes, eat the fork too! Yes! Yes! Nom! Giving you the fork.
フォークも食べてくれた、優しい！
You even ate the fork, how kind!
ルーナも食べさせてあげるね
Luna will feed you too, right.
え、みんなじゃルーナのこの、食いかけ食べろがいいの？
Eh, everyone, is it good to eat Luna's leftover bite?
はい、もっと食べて！みんな食べて、ほら、ほら、ほら！あ、食べたなら
Yes, eat more! Everyone eat, hey, hey, hey! Ah, if you ate...
はい！食べた！フォークも食べるのだな！
Yes! You ate it! You're eating the fork too!
食べさせてくれた！ありがとう！
You fed me! Thank you!
でこれ、ルーナ本当にプレゼントありがとう！
And Luna, seriously, thank you for the present!
マジで、あの、ケーキ持ってきたよって言った瞬間の祭りのガチリアルな反応見せたよ
Seriously, showing Matsuri's genuinely real reaction the moment I said "I brought the cake."
さあ、隠してしまったからね、ルーナにね
Well, since I hid it from Luna, you know.
ルーナはうん。だってルーナもお祝いしてもらったからね。祭りの先輩にもお返ししたいなって思ってたの
Luna, yeah. Because Luna was also celebrated. I wanted to return the favor to Matsuri-senpai too.
思ってたの！ありがとうね！
You thought that! Thank you!
はい、ありがとうございます。そんなね、こと言ってくれて嬉しいですよ
Yes, thank you very much. I'm so happy you said such things.
はい。何、なんすか、普通に
Yes. What, what is it, normally.
何でもルーナのこと本当に大好きだよ
Anyway, I really love Luna.
恥ずかしい！何々？
Embarrassing! What, what?
いやいやいや、まあまあ、まあまあ、ということでね
No no no, well well, well well, so with that said...
続いていきましょうか？ね？
Shall we continue? Right?
うん。はい。というわけで続いてはですね
Yeah. Yes. So, moving on...
あの、ルーナたん、ん？は、あれですよね？何？
Um, Luna-tan, hmm? That is, right? What?
演技力はありますか？もちろん！なのだな！
Do you have acting skills? Of course! You do!
超、あの、やりたいことがあって、うん。ま、祭り
Super, um, there's something I want to do, yeah. Well, Matsuri...
さんざん受けてって言われてるわけですよ、フェスティバルーナで
You've been told you get lots of laughs at Festival Luna.
もう、全然正しくない！全然正しくなくて
Man, that's not right at all! Not right at all,
ちょっと、今回、うん。それ証明したいので
So this time, yeah. To prove that,
一緒にエチュードをしていきましょう
Let's do an etude together.
エチュード？
An etude?
はい、ということで、ててえエチュード！いえーい！
Yes, so, Teetee Etude! Yay! Yay!
え、では、テーマは「教室で2人きりになった夏色祭と姫森ルーナ」
Eh, well, the theme is "Natsuiro Matsuri and Himemori Luna left alone together in a classroom."
さあ、どんなことが起きてしまうのでしょうか？
Now, what kind of things are going to happen?
その一部始終は、動画などに撮って、こちらのハッシュタグでツイートしてくださいね
Be sure to record the whole sequence in videos or such, and tweet with this hashtag.
ということで、うん。祭りが攻めあがるから
With that said, yeah. Matsuri's going to press the attack, so
いやいやいや、リスナーさんそんなの求めてないからね！何言ってんだ
No no no, the listeners aren't asking for that! What are you saying?
だってさ、君がやりたいとか、何言ってんだ
I mean, you said you wanted to do it, what are you talking about?
何が！何が！何言ってんだもう！祭りだってさ、なんだよもう、何が、演技力！
What! What! What are you talking about! Even Matsuri, come on, what, acting skills!
いや、誕生日だからちょっと、気合って
Well, since it's my birthday, put some spirit into it.
いや、誕生日だから、しょうがないのはね
Well, since it's my birthday, it can't be helped, right.
じゃ、ちょっと、祭り向こうから出てくるからルーナ教室で待ってて
Well, Matsuri will come out from over there, so Luna wait in the classroom.
わかったのだな
Got it.
行くよ
Here I go.
じゃあ行きます。夏色祭と姫森ルーナのガチで打ち合わせ無しのててえエチュードまで、3、2、1、キュッ！
Here we go. Natsuiro Matsuri and Himemori Luna's genuinely unscripted, heartwarming etude, in 3, 2, 1, cue!
ルーナ？
Luna?
お、祭りの先輩どうしたのだな？
Oh, Matsuri-senpai, what's wrong?
あの、ちょっと、言いたいことがあってさ
Um, I have something to say, you see.
なんなのだ？
What is it?
あのね、ルーナには言ってなかったんだけどさ、
You see, I hadn't told Luna this, but...
なんでさ、あの
Why, um...
なんなのだ！なんなのだ！違うんだよ
What is it! What is it! That's not it!
ルーナのこと、別に照れてねえんだよ。照れてないよ、別に
I'm not acting shy about Luna or anything. I'm not shy at all.
本当に照れてねえよ！ルーナのこと好きだよ
I'm really not shy! I like Luna.
知ってる
I know.
いや、そういうのじゃなくて、そういうのじゃなくて本当に好きだよ。だからさ、
No, not like that, not like that, I really like you. So,
チューしてもいい？
Can I kiss you?
チューさっきされたのだ
You kissed me earlier.
ちゃんと口でして
Do it properly with your mouth.
え、それはちょっとまずいのだな。ちょっとここでするのはここはちょっと公の場だからさ
Eh, that's a bit bad. Doing it right here is kind of a public place, you see.
え、ちょっと恥ずかしいのわかるのだ。ちょっとちょっと恥ずかしいんだ。照れてなくてもいいんだよ
Eh, I know it's a bit embarrassing. It's a bit embarrassing. It's okay even if you're not shy.
ルーナ、もうちょっと先輩いいのかな
Luna, is senpai alright with this?
ここでいいのな、みんなに見られてしまうのだよ
Is it really okay here, people are going to see us.
それが愛じゃん
That's what love is.
ルーナ
Luna.
そうそうなのよね。祭り攻めでしょ？できるんだよ、ちゃんと攻め
That's right. Matsuri's attacking, right? You can do it, attack properly.
なんかめっちゃ引っ張られてる
Somehow I'm being dragged along so much.
え、いいの？うーん、もういい、いいのだよ
Eh, is it okay? Yeah, already good, it's fine.
いいのだよ
It's fine.
どう？どう？
How is it? How is it?
How is it?
ちょっと！
Wait, wait!
おい、どうだった？
Hey, how was it?
いやいやいやいや、いやいやいや。
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
どうでした祭？攻めてきてた？
How was it, Matsuri? Did you come at all?
まあ、最初はね。
Well, at first, yeah.
うん。
Yeah.
後半ちょっと...いやいやいやいや。
Later on, sort of... no, wait, wait, wait.
それがまあ本当の祭りですかね。
That was like the "real festival," right?
あ、最後が？
Ah, the end was?
いや、最後緊張して...
Yeah, the very end was just...
最初はちょっと頑張っちゃった...
At first, I was a bit, you know, trying too hard,
で、最後がね、全然素でいた！素で！
and then the end was completely bare! Bare!
素で！
So bare!
もっと照れていたならね、後半ちょっと押され気味になってて...あ、分かった分かった、はいはいはい。
If I was being too shy, the second half got a bit pushy, right? Ah, okay, okay, okay.
ということでね。
So, you know...
おい、のり、顔隠してんのこれ！
Wait, Luna, you're hiding your face, look at this!
お前がやるのかよ、顔隠すのに！
Why are you hiding your face when you're the one doing it?
恥ずかしがってんじゃねえよ！おい！うるさいな！
You're getting all embarrassed now, Luna! Hey!
おい！
Hey!
人の話聞いてるか？おいおいおいおいおいおいおい。
Hey, are you listening? Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
そんなこと言ってなんとも思ってないからね！
I'm not thinking anything like that at all, you know!
めちゃ聞いてんだよ！いやもうもうしゃ...
She's totally listening, right? Yeah, yeah, I'm happy.
こいこいこい！ばいばい！
Hey, hey, hey, hey! Bye-bye!
ちょっと！待って待って、先輩！
Wait, hey! Stop, stop! Senpai!
待って待って、先輩！
Wait, wait, Senpai!
ルナが来たぞー！
Luna came!
ルナ！ルナ！ルナ！
Luna! Luna! Luna!
危ねぇ！おい、できた！
Hey, that was close! Hey, we made it!
ルナ！授業遅れるぞ！走った！
Luna! We're late for class! Let's go!
はあ、できた！ルナ！ルナ！
Ah, we made it! Luna! Luna!
ルナなら遅いから、スキップで握れる。
Luna, we're slow, so let's skip and hold hands!
ルナ！ルナ！ルナが、やり切った！
Luna! Luna! Luna! We made it!
ルナ！ルナ！
Luna! Luna!
息もできない！ルナ！ルナ！
I can't even breathe, Luna! Luna!
ルナが、やり切った！ルナ！ルナ！
Luna! We made it! Luna! Luna!
ルナ！ルナ！ルナが、やり切った！
Luna! Luna! Luna! We made it!
ルナ！ルナ！やり切った！
Luna! Luna! We made it!
ルナが来たぞー！
Luna came!
ルナ！ルナ！ルナ！
Luna! Luna! Luna!
危ねぇ！おい、できた！
Hey, that was close! Hey, we made it!
ルナ！授業遅れるぞ！走った！
Luna! We're late for class! Let's go!
はあ、できた！ルナ！ルナ！
Ah, we made it! Luna! Luna!
ルナなら遅いから、スキップで握れる。
Luna, we're slow, so let's skip and hold hands!
ルナ！ルナ！ルナが、やり切った！
Luna! Luna! Luna! We made it!
ルナ！ルナ！
Luna! Luna!
息もできない！ルナ！ルナ！
I can't even breathe, Luna! Luna!
ルナが、やり切った！ルナ！ルナ！
Luna! We made it! Luna! Luna!
ルナ！ルナ！ルナが、やり切った！
Luna! Luna! Luna! We made it!
ルナ！ルナ！やり切った！
Luna! Luna! We made it!
ルナが来たぞー！
Luna came!
ルナ！ルナ！ルナ！
Luna! Luna! Luna!
危ねぇ！おい、できた！
Hey, that was close! Hey, we made it!
ルナ！授業遅れるぞ！走った！
Luna! We're late for class! Let's go!
はあ、できた！ルナ！ルナ！
Ah, we made it! Luna! Luna!
ルナなら遅いから、スキップで握れる。
Luna, we're slow, so let's skip and hold hands!
ルナ！ルナ！ルナが、やり切った！
Luna! Luna! Luna! We made it!
ルナ！ルナ！
Luna! Luna!
息もできない！ルナ！ルナ！
I can't even breathe, Luna! Luna!
ルナが、やり切った！ルナ！ルナ！
Luna! We made it! Luna! Luna!
ルナ！ルナ！ルナが、やり切った！
Luna! Luna! Luna! We made it!
ルナ！ルナ！やり切った！
Luna! Luna! We made it!
いや、ここまで来たらね、
Man, if we've come this far,
さすがにルナもね、追いつかないでしょ。
even Luna won't be able to catch up, right?
あの人体力ないっすね。
That person has no stamina, you know.
ん？
Oh?
あ、なんだ、ルナのね、顔ハメパネルがね、あるだけなんですね。
Ah, I see. It's just Luna's cardboard panel, right?
はい。
Yeah.
ということで皆さん、ブロードウェイに来ましたよ！いえーい！
So everyone, we've come to Broadway! Yay!
いえーい！
Yay!
ここはこぢんまりとしたステージでございますね。
It's a cozy little stage, isn't it?
ちょっと何でパネルがあるのかね、よくわかんないんですけども。
I'm not quite sure why there's a panel here, though.
まあ、ブロードウェイに来たことだし、ちょっとね雰囲気変えて撮影タイムしちゃいましょうか。
Well, since we came to Broadway, let's change the mood and do a photo shoot time!
で、セクシーなね祭りも魅せたいなって思うんで。
I want to show off the fancy festival outfit, too.
それではさっそく、カメラマンさん、撮ってください。
So cameraman, please take some pictures.
ちょっとパネルある、隣で撮るか。
Is the panel right next to me?
ど、どうですか？
How is it?
おい、もしやしてねえ、ルナや...
Wait, is she moving? Luna?
おい！
Hey!
なに？おい！出てきた！
What? Hey! She came out!
ル、ルナ？おい、パネルだったのではないの？
Luna? Hey, wasn't this a panel?
パネルじゃねえのよ！違うの？動いてた！
It wasn't a panel? She was moving?
ルナは何だったの？まさか、まさかパネルが喋ると思わなかったからちょっとびっくりしちゃった。
Luna? Wait, she was moving the whole time? No way, no way!
ちょっと、ちょっと待って
Wait, wait, wait a second.
分かった、分かった
Okay, I got it, I got it.
じゃあ、しょうがないからルナも一緒にセクシーな感じで撮影会一緒にしましょう。
Well, since it can't be helped, Luna will join you and we'll do a sexy photoshoot together!
いいのな？
Are you sure?
いいよ、いいよ。
Yeah, sure.
ヤッター！嬉しい！
Yay! I'm so happy!
じゃ、それもねツイートしてください皆さん。
So everyone, please tweet that out too!
じゃあどんな、どんなのがいいとかルナ。
So what kind of poses do you want, Luna?
ええ、あの...祭りかセメっぽいのがいい。
Um... something like Matsuri-sempai would be good.
いや、そんな要らない。
No, we don't need that.
え、なんで？
Eh, why?
そんなの誰も求めてないから！誰も求めてない。
Nobody's asking for that! Nobody's asking for it!
みんながツイートしたくなるような可愛いのにするの！
We should do cute ones that everyone would want to tweet!
可愛いの？可愛いのってどんな感じ？
Cute? What kind of cute?
可愛い？可愛い。
Cute? Cute.
あ、じゃあちょっと...
Ah, then let's...
なんで近くない？近い！近っ！
Why are you so close? Close! So close!
え、ないない、別にいい...
Eh, no no, it's fine...
いいけど、なんでちょっと離れる？
It's fine, but why are you backing away?
いやじゃあ、近く、近く、さっきまで...
No, close, close, until just now...
あ、近いね、はい。どうですか皆さん。
Ah, close, yes. How is it, everyone?
やっほー！うふふ、ウインク可愛いね。
Yoo-hoo! Hehe, that wink is cute.
可愛い。
So cute.
まあデブセパ顔でかかね？
Well, chubby-sempai's face is big, huh?
これでいいでしょ。
This is fine, right?
インキホウなのだ！
It's ink-ho!
まあデブセパ前出て、前、前！
Well, chubby-sempai, step forward, front, front!
前出て、前出て。あら、むすいさ。
Step forward, step forward. Oh, muscle-chan.
上でこうやってこうやって立ってやってて。
Standing up like this on top and doing it.
ポーズ良くない？
Isn't this pose good?
トーテムポール！
Totem pole!
可愛い。
Cute.
あぶな！大丈夫、大丈夫。
Whoa! It's okay, it's okay.
ちょっと、ちょっと、あのさ、この角と角のくぼみあるじゃん。あそこにてぃっかてぃっかあててるのな。
Hey, hey, you know, there's the indent between the horns, right? She's putting it right there.
てぃっかてぃっかあててんのな。
She's putting it right there.
あと、これやりたい。
Also, I want to do this.
あ、いいのね。
Ah, that's good.
フュージョン！はー！
Fusion! Haa!
可愛い。
Cute.
いい感じなのね。
It's a good vibe.
あと、ハートとかね。
Also, hearts and stuff.
あ、ハートいいのね。
Ah, hearts are good.
どうして羊とできなかったんだっけ？
Why couldn't we do it with sheep?
あ、そうなんかね。
Ah, is that so.
あれ、祭りセパじゃねえの？
Wait, isn't that Matsuri-sempai?
いや、違うよ。
No, that's wrong.
ハート！ハート！ぽっしゅ！
Heart! Heart! Posh!
可愛い。
Cute.
可愛いね。
So cute.
ほっしゅ大丈夫？
Posh, are you okay?
なんで！？なんで息切れすんのそれだけで。
Why?! Why are you out of breath just from that?
ルナはワイドバランスできる？
Can Luna do a wide balance?
え、なに、なに、なんなの？
Eh, what, what, what is that?
ワイドバランスして？とかやってみたのな。
"Can you do a wide balance?" I tried doing that.
マツリサキケーって言われちゃったからさ。
Because people told me "Matsuri, you're K."
そんなのできるわけねえだろ！なによりよ。
There's no way I can do that! First of all.
可愛い、可愛いぞ。
Cute, cute.
可愛いのが限界なのだよ。
Being cute is my limit.
あとはね、背中合わせとか撮りたい。
Also, I want to take a back-to-back photo.
あ、背中。
Ah, back-to-back.
ポージングで...ちょっとポージング慣れてない...まだデビューしたてなんです。この子許してあげてください。
Posing... I'm not used to posing... She just debuted. Please forgive this child.
これからポーズ取ることも増えてくるから大丈夫！大体
We'll be taking poses more often from now on, so it's fine! Generally...
あの、あれだよ。グー、チョキ、パーを使えばポーズはできるんですよ。
Um, you know. If you use rock, paper, scissors, you can do poses.
あ、グーチョキパーなのだ？
Ah, rock-paper-scissors?
グーチョキパー、例えば、パーでこれとか、あと、そのあとにチョキでやって、そのあとグーでやる とかで、もう3種類できるじゃん。
Rock, paper, scissors, for example, doing this with paper, then doing scissors after, then doing rock, you can do three types already.
あ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
そのパーを片手でにしてみたりとか、角度変えるだけで、ね？
Just making that paper with one hand or changing the angle, see?
みんなのね。
Everyone's.
そうそうそう。ね？いいのだね。可愛い。
Right, right, right. See? It's good. Cute.
ということでですね、皆さん、可愛く撮ってくれましたか？
So everyone, did you take cute pictures of us?
撮れました？
Did you?
はい！ということでですね、じゃあ続いていきましょう。
Yes! So then, let's continue.
続いての企画はですね、
The next project is,
さっきは、ま、ジェスチャーゲームしたんですけど、
earlier we did a gesture game, but
今度は、ま、みんなが知っているであろう曲に合わせてね、ジェスチャーゲームをしていきたいと思います！
this time, we're going to do a gesture game to songs that everyone probably knows!
それじゃあ、
So then,
無音ジェスチャーダンスゲーム！
Silent Gesture Dance Game!
はい、ということで、ルール説明をしていきます。
Right, so I'll explain the rules.
今から祭りがね、あの、曲のリズムに合わせてとか振付けに合わせてとかではなく、歌詞に合わせてジェスチャーをしていきます。ダンスとはちょっと違うかなって感じなんですけど、
From now on, Matsuri will do gestures according to the lyrics, not to the song's rhythm or choreography. It feels a bit different from dancing, but
あの、聞いてる、祭りが聞いてる曲はみんなには流れません。
um, the song Matsuri is listening to won't play for everyone.
このズンズン、チャーツンズンチャーツンが流れていきますよ。
This "zun-zun, cha-tsun-zun, cha-tsun" will play instead.
なので、祭りのジェスチャーを見て歌詞を想像して曲名を お答えください！
So please watch Matsuri's gestures, imagine the lyrics, and answer the song title!
はい。
Yes.
ということで、じゃあ早速、ま、2曲あるのでね、やっていきますよ。
So, let's get right into it. There are 2 songs, so we'll do them.
じゃあ、まず1曲目！
Well, first song!
よーーい、スタート！
Rea--dy, start!
おっ？
Oh?
うわ！
Woah!
あ、すごい！みんな！
Ah, amazing! Everyone!
あれれれ？ すごいのら、みんな！いい感じな！
Huh? Amazing, nora? Everyone, looking good!
いい感じな
Looking good.
おっ、すごい！ さすがみんな、わかってるならねー！
Oh, amazing! As expected, you guys get it, huh!
おっ、おっ、みんな！みんなおててやってるのだよ、これ！
Oh, oh, everyone! Everyone's doing the hand gestures, look!
すごいのは！まつりちゃんのせーぱつ、すげえ表現やめるのら！
Amazing, nora! Matsuri-chan's seb-- crazy expression, stop it!
おっ、完璧！
Oh, perfect!
完璧すぎな！
Too perfect!
可愛いのだ、じゃみんな！まっつんのせーぱついっぱい、みんな取らなー！
Cute, right everyone? Matsuri-chan's seb-- get lots of them, everyone!
スクショして！スクショして！
Take a screenshot! Take a screenshot!
うわあ、迫ってきな！ うわあ、激しい動き！
Woah, closing in! Woah, intense movement!
こう交渉かけたなら！ うわあ、ジャンプした！
If you negotiated like this! Woah, jumped!
はぁ、はぁ、はぁ！
Haah, haah, haah!
息切れしてるのよ、ねえ！
I'm running out of breath, hey!
これ分かったかな？いいのだね！
Did you figure this out? That's right, huh!
はい！というわけで、
Yes! So,
ルーナはね、もうわかった？
Luna, you already figured it out?
もうわかったのだ！コメントにもいっぱい書いてある！
I already figured it out! There's lots written in the comments too!
本当ですか？
Really?
みんなすごい当ててるのだよ！
Everyone's guessing it so well!
ということね、
So,
じゃあ、もう１回同じ動きが、今ノリと勢いでやったんで同じ動きは多分できませんが、
Well, let's do the same movement again—since I just did it with momentum, I probably can't do the exact same movement, but
なんとなくね、やっていきましょう！
somewhat, let's go do it!
うん、それでは正解はこちらです！
Yup, well then, the correct answer is right here!
『Say!ファンファーレ！』
"Say! Fanfare!"
(うーっ、Go!) (いえーい！)
(Woo, Go!) (Yeah!)
(はい！はい！) (うーっ、こんこん！)
(Hai! Hai!) (Woo, Konkon!)
(せーのっ！) (Are you ready?)
(Ready?!) (Are you ready?)
ほーっとひと息お茶ですよ (はい、どーぞ！)
Take a breather with some tea (Here you go!)
いつもの場所から元気にせーのでご挨拶 (おっはこーんーでーすよー！) 始めましょう！
Greeting you cheerfully from our usual place ("Good con-con-con-day-su-yo!") Let's begin!
おしゃべりをしてゲームと過ごす そんな毎日が愛しくて
Chatting and spending time with games, loving days like these,
あれもこれも手を出しがちです
I tend to reach out for this and that.
歌とかステージはまだまだ恥ずかしいけど
Singing and stages are still a bit embarrassing, but
支えあってほら 届けますよ この声を
Supporting each other, look, I'll deliver this voice to you.
Say! ほら その顔上げて (Yeah!) みんなで手を取れば (Fuwa...)
Say! Look, raise your face (Yeah!) If everyone holds hands (Fuwa...)
Dive! まだまだ道の途中 世界を越えよう
Dive! We're still on the way, let's cross the world!
Say! ほら 推しお仕事も (Yeah!) 止まらない全力ですから！ (Fuwa...)
Say! Look, even our favorite work (Yeah!) Is unstoppable at full power! (Fuwa...)
夢を書きかえたら 追いかけ続けよう
If we rewrite our dreams, let's keep chasing them!
ともに (はい！) 繋ぐ (はい！) ファンファーレ (Go!) (いえーい！)
Together (Hai!) Connect (Hai!) Fanfare (Go!) (Yeah!)
ということで、 Say! ファンファーレでしたー！
And with that, it was "Say! Fanfare!"!
めっちゃアイドルなのら！
Such an idol, nora!
ダンスではないからね、歌詞に合わせて歌詞っぽい動きをしたつもりではいます！
It's not dance choreography, but I tried to do movements fitting the lyrics!
すごいのだね！一番分かりやすかったのは…
Amazing, nora! The easiest to understand was...
うーん、こんこん！
Hmm, kon-kon!
なんとそこ？そこで分かったの？
What, there? You figured it out there?
うーん、こんこん！だと思ったよね。ねこーん！
Yup, thought it was kon-kon! Neko-n!
はい、当たった人はいますかね？分かりやすかったかな？
Yes, are there people who got it right? Was it easy to understand?
どうだったかな？すごい、いっぱいあったのだよ、「せーの、ファンファーレ」ってコメントがいっぱいあったのだよ！
How was it? Amazing, there were lots—"Ready, Fanfare", there were so many comments like that!
さすがでございます！さすがないのら！
As expected of you! Truly amazing, nora!
はい、続いて、2曲目！2曲目なのだよ！
Yes, moving on to the 2nd song! The second song, nora!
まぁ、これはね、みんな知ってるんじゃないかな？って思います。
Well, for this one, I think everyone probably knows it, right?
はい、それでは、続いての曲いきますよ！いいかなみんな？ はい、レッツ、スタート！
Yes, then let's go to the next song! Ready everyone? Yes, let's start!
おっ、これは？
Oh, what's this?
これはみんな分かったのだな？ おおおお！
Did everyone figure this out? Oooo!
あ、いろいろ、いろのこまんどあるのだよねー。ふむふむふむ。
Ah, there are various color commands, right. Hmm hmm hmm.
あーーー、なるほど！
Aaaah, I see!
みんな、まっつんじゃなくてせんぱいをよく見るのだな！
Everyone, look closely at the senpai, not Matsuri!
おお！指差してる、指差してる！おお！
Oh! Pointing, pointing! Oh!
そしてる指そしてる！
Pointing their fingers!
むねきゅんなのだな！
Heart-pounding, nora!
あーー！なんか、みんな！
Aaaah! Like, everyone!
うーー！ うーー！ うーー！ なんとも言えない！みんな！みんな！みんな！
Uuu! Uuu! Uuu! Can't really describe it! Everyone! Everyone! Everyone!
ほらほらほら！ほらほらほらほら！ めっちゃジャンプしてる！めっちゃジャンプしてる！
Look look look! Look look look look! Jumping so much! Jumping so much!
あーーー！ めっちゃ愛ののしてる！
Aaaah! Showing so much love!
答え出てこねえんだよな、これ。
I can't quite figure out the answer, huh.
みんなね、うーん、そう、なんかね、もうなんて言えばいいんだろ、答えは言えないんだけど、あ、あー...
Everyone, um... yeah. Like, how should I put it? I can't give you the answer yet, but...
え、待って、みんな、みんなダメだ、無理！
Wait, everyone... No, everyone, this is impossible!
あれ、答え？無理！
Wait, the answer? No way!
結構頑張ったんだよでも。みんな...
I tried pretty hard though. Everyone...
これはね、難しいですね。これ一人ね、出てたんですよ、出てたのよ。みんなファンサっていう意見が多かったんだけど
This one's pretty tough. One person actually got it right earlier. A lot of people guessed 'Fan Service', but...
めっちゃ超王道なんだね。まあもう、ホロライブ好きならわかるんじゃないかなっていう曲ですので。じゃあ、正解行きましょうか。それでは、正解はこちらです！
It's super orthodox. Well, since it's a Hololive fan favorite, you should get it. So, let's reveal the answer. Here it is!
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn heartbeats echo!
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the best time and the best friends,
キラメキに乗って☆
riding on the sparkle☆
(イェーイ！)
(Yeah!)
覚えているかな？ 最初の歌（懐かしいね）
Do you remember? Our very first song (So nostalgic)
私 声が震えていた（ほんの少し）
My voice was trembling (Just a little bit)
あの日から続く未来は
The future continuing from that day,
みんなと掴んだ今日だよ
is today that we grasped together with everyone.
もっともっともっともっと 加速するハート
More, more, more, more, accelerating heart!
（一緒に）行くよどこまでも
(Together) Let's go anywhere!
(Are you ready?) 準備はOK？
(Are you ready?) Is your preparation OK?
ひらけ!! 夢のトビラを（1 2 3）
Open up!! The door of dreams (1, 2, 3)
（キラメキライダー）
(Kirameki Rider)
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn heartbeats echo!
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the best time and the best friends,
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
I'm right here because you found me.
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ みんなで歌おう 終わらないメロディ
I wanted to see you and came here. Let's sing together, an endless melody!
キラメキに乗って☆
Riding on the sparkle☆
そういうことだったんだね
So that's how it was!
最後乗っててたんだね、実況でさ
You were riding at the end during the commentary!
いやね、分かった人いるかな？ 分かった人すごいね。
Man, I wonder if anyone figured it out? Anyone who did is amazing.
はい、ということでどうでしたか、無音ジェスチャーゲーム。みんなもぜひね、ホロライブの曲とかそうじゃない曲でも遊んでみてね。
So, how was it? The silent charades game. Everyone, please try playing it with Hololive songs or other songs too!
ということでね、今日はね、Lunaちゃんも来てくれてありがとうございます本当に。
So yeah, thank you so much Luna-chan for coming today!
あ、お邪魔しまーすの、ね、はい、近いの、近いよ、もう...
Ah, 'Excuse me for barging in'—yeah. Close, you're close!
今日は、まつり先輩、お誕生日おめでとう！
Today is Matsuri-senpai's birthday—Happy Birthday!
実はね、まつり先輩にサプライズが...あるの？
Actually, there's a surprise for Matsuri-senpai... Is there?
お誕生日プレゼント、どーん！
A birthday present, ta-da!
なになに、泣いちゃった！
What, what? You're crying!
まつり先輩、お誕生日本当におめでとう！
Matsuri-senpai, happy birthday, truly!
開けていいですか？大騒ぎ...
Can I open it? Making a fuss...
開けて、開けて、開けて、開けて、ありがとう。
Open it, open it, open it, open it! Thank you.
あのね、それね、まつり先輩、めっちゃかわいいピアノなの。
Um, you see, Matsuri-senpai, it's a super cute piano.
まつい先輩とお揃っち！ありがとう！
Matching with Matsui-senpai! Thank you!
なになになに！？めちゃかわいい！ありがとう！
What, what, what?! So cute! Thank you!
え？なになになに？パジャマなんだからね！？
Eh? What, what, what? It's pajamas, you know?!
お泊まり会する？
Are we having a sleepover?
そういうことにするの！
Let's go with that!
お泊まり会する？
A sleepover?
そういうことにするの！
Let's go with that!
お泊まり会だー！やったー！
It's a sleepover! Yay!
お揃いのパジャマなんだからね！？
Matching pajamas, you know?!
え、お揃いのパジャマなんだからね！？
Eh, matching pajamas, you know?!
ありがとうなの！やったー！
Thank you! Yay!
よかったね、分かってくれて。
I'm glad you understood.
ありがとうございます本当に。
Thank you so much, really.
いいのよいいのよ。
It's fine, it's fine.
いつもお世話になってるし。
I've always taken care of you.
いいのよいつもお世話になってるし。
It's fine, you've always taken care of me.
本当に！おめでとうなのだ！
Really! Congratulations!
まつり先輩、ルーナね、
Matsuri-senpai, Luna...
今日ここに居てくれて本当に！ありがとうなのだよ！
Thank you so much for being here today!
ありがとうなのだよ！
Thank you so much!
これからは、まつり先輩、ルーナと一緒に活動してくれたら嬉しいな…。ぜひお願いします！
From now on, Matsuri-senpai, I'd be so happy if you could do activities together with Luna... Please, I'm begging you!
お願いしますなのだ！
I'm begging you!
みんなありがとう！本当にありがとう！嬉しいな、パジャマって！
Thank you everyone! Thank you so much! I'm so happy, pajamas!
めっちゃ泣いてるの…。みんなめっちゃ泣いてる…。まつり先輩、昨日も、今日も泣いてるのな。
You're crying so much... Everyone's crying so much... Matsuri-senpai, you cried yesterday and today too.
だって、こんな…こんなプレゼントなんて貰うことないじゃないですか！ありがとう！今日から着るね！
Because... I never get presents like this! Thank you! I'll wear it starting today!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ということでね、皆さん本当にありがとうございます！ルーナも本当にありがとう！よかったで…
So everyone, thank you truly so much! Luna, thank you really too! I'm glad...
あの、今からね、みんなにもルーナにも…気持ちを込めて、最後にお歌を歌って、いこうかなと思うので、ぜひ皆さんもルーナも聴いてください。
Um, from now on, putting our feelings into it for everyone and Luna too, I want to go sing a song at the end, so everyone and Luna please listen too.
歌えるかな？
Can we sing it?
頑張るぞー！
We'll do our best!
はーい！
Yay!
なんのらが来たぞー！
Nanora has come!
なんのら、なんのら、なんのらがやってきた！
Nanora, nanora, nanora has arrived!
なんのら、しゅうかいおくれるぞ、ふぁいたー！
Nanora, you're gonna be late for roll call, fighter!
はやい！
Fast!
やあ、できた！
Yay, we made it!
なんのら、遅いからスキップで握れる
Nanora, you're slow, so you can skip and grab it!
なんのら、なんのら、なんのらがやってきた！
Nanora, nanora, nanora has arrived!
なんのら、キャッキャッキャッキャッ
Nanora, kyakkakkyakka!
びみなんてない、なんのら、なんのら、なんのらがやってきた！
There's no taste/beauty, nanora, nanora, nanora has arrived!
なんのら、なんのら、なんのらがやってきた！
Nanora, nanora, nanora has arrived!
なんのら、しゅうかいおくれるぞ、ふぁいたー！
Nanora, you're gonna be late for roll call, fighter!
はやい！やあ、できた！
Fast! Yay, we made it!
なんのらが来たぞー！
Nanora has come!
なんのら、なんのら、なんのらがやってきた！
Nanora, nanora, nanora has arrived!
なんのら、しゅうかいおくれるぞ、ふぁいたー！はやい！
Nanora, you're gonna be late for roll call, fighter! Fast!
やあ、できた！
Yay, we made it!
なんのら、遅いからスキップで握れる
Nanora, you're slow, so you can skip and grab it!
なんのら、なんのら、なんのらがやってきた！
Nanora, nanora, nanora has arrived!
なんのら、キャッキャッキャッキャッ
Nanora, kyakkakkyakka!
びみなんてない、なんのら、なんのら、なんのらがやってきた！
There's no taste, nanora, nanora, nanora has arrived!
なんのら、なんのら、なんのらがやってきた！
Nanora, nanora, nanora has arrived!
なんのら、しゅうかいおくれるぞ、ふぁいたー！
Nanora, you're gonna be late for roll call, fighter!
なんのらが来たぞー！
Nanora has come!
なんのら、なんのら、なんのらがやってきた！
Nanora, nanora, nanora has arrived!
なんのら、しゅうかいおくれるぞ、ふぁいたー！はやい！
Nanora, you're gonna be late for roll call, fighter! Fast!
なんのら、遅いからスキップで握れる
Nanora, you're slow, so you can skip and grab it!
なんのら、なんのら、なんのらがやってきた！
Nanora, nanora, nanora has arrived!
なんのら、キャッキャッキャッキャッ
Nanora, kyakkakkyakka!
びみなんてない、なんのら、なんのら、なんのらがやってきた！
There's no taste, nanora, nanora, nanora has arrived!
なんのら、なんのら、なんのらがやってきた！
Nanora, nanora, nanora has arrived!
なんのら、しゅうかいおくれるぞ、ふぁいたー！
Nanora, you're gonna be late for roll call, fighter!
なんのらが来たぞー！
Nanora has come!
なんのら, なんのら, なんのらがやってきた！
Nanora, nanora, nanora has arrived!
なんのら、しゅうかいおくれるぞ、ふぁいたー！はやい！
Nanora, you're gonna be late for roll call, fighter! Fast!
なんのら、遅いからスキップで握れる
Nanora, you're slow, so you can skip and grab it!
なんのら、なんのら、なんのらがやってきた！
Nanora, nanora, nanora has arrived!
できた！
Done!
夏色まつりができた！
Natsuiro Matsuri is ready!
同じ未来を見ていたい
I want to see the same future,
あの夢手に行きたい
I want to reach that dream.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れgo!
Running with our own unique hearts, go!
走れーーー！
Run!
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
In a pitch-black place, hope sprouted,
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われた
my eyes were stolen by that tiny hope.
不安で揺れる心を上手くチューニングして
Tuning my heart that trembled with anxiety,
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
I mustered up a tiny bit of courage.
諦めの文字デリートして進む
Deleting the word "give up" and moving forward,
苦しいときも もう私はいちばん…じゃなくてひとりじゃないから
even when it's hard, I'm not alone anymore.
だからもっと夢追いかけたい
That's why I want to chase my dreams even more,
ワクワク止まらない
my excitement won't stop.
想像を超えてく 世界見せてあげる
Surpassing imagination, I'll show you the world.
アクセスしてみたい 後悔なんてそうさせない
I want to access it, and never allow any regrets.
それぞれ違った ココロで彩れ
Coloring it with our own unique hearts.
走れーーー！
Run!
碧空の空に輝くまぶしい思い出は
The dazzling memories shining in the blue sky,
見たことのない光を リアルに届けるよ
delivering a light never seen before, realistically.
いつも聞こえるエールは ここにキャプチャーして
Capturing the cheers I always hear right here,
また新しい光を探したくなるよ
it makes me want to search for a new light.
君の笑顔は 保存して進む
Saving your smile as I move forward,
悲しいときに見返すよ 力が湧くから
I'll look back at it when I'm sad, because it gives me strength.
胸を張って夢追いかけたい
Holding my head high, I want to chase my dreams,
奇跡のストーリー
a miraculous story.
一緒に作ろう
Let's create it together,
終わらない夢を
a never-ending dream.
誰一人欠かせない 愛が舞ったこの世界
This world where love dances, where no one is missing.
それぞれ違ったココロで彩れ
Coloring it with our own unique hearts.
走れーーー！
Run!
皆今日は本当にありがとう！
Thank you all so much today!
ここに嬉しいです。同期のみんなとかね、後輩とかもね、
I'm so happy. My gen-mates and juniors too,
あの、いっぱい増えてホロライブで本当に良かったなって思います。
have grown so much, and I'm really glad I joined Hololive.
本当に本当に大好きだよ。ありがとう。
I really, truly love you all. Thank you.
忘れずにこの言葉、練習続けたい。
Without forgetting these words, I want to keep practicing.
終わらない世界に溢れ出すよ 笑顔たち
Overflowing into a never-ending world, smiles...
憧れの舞台立ちたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams,
らしく輝きたい
I want to shine in my own way.
時に涙して また笑い合いたい
Sometimes crying, yet laughing together again.
同じ未来を見たい
I want to see the same future,
あの夢手にしたい
I want to hold that dream in my hands.
踏み出そう奇跡の一歩を
Let's take that miraculous first step.
息き切らせて夢追いかけたい
Out of breath, I want to chase my dreams,
ワクワク止まらない
my excitement won't stop.
想像を超えてく 世界見せてあげる
Surpassing imagination, I'll show you the world.
アクセスしてみたい？ 後悔なんてここにない
Want to try accessing? There are no regrets here.
それぞれ違ったココロで
With our own unique hearts...
ありがとうございました！シャイニースマイリーストーリーでした！
Thank you very much! That was "Shiny Smily Story"!
皆さん聞いてくれてありがとう！
Thank you everyone for listening!
そして最後はやっぱりこのアイドル衣装ですよね！
And lastly, it's definitely this idol outfit, right?!
めっちゃかわいいでしょ！ありがとうございます！
It's super cute, isn't it?! Thank you so much!
撮ってる時、歓声があまりそんなになったんですけど、なんとかね、最後は抑えましたよ。
When I was filming, there wasn't much cheering, but somehow I managed to keep it down at the end.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
そしてですね、えー今日はですね、まあよくやるんですけど祭りは。
And today... well, Matsuri often does this,
今日は祭りにあの、お手紙をね、書いて、来ましたので、ちょっとここで読ませていただきたいなと思います。
but today, I've written a letter to Matsuri, so I'd like to read it for you here.
それではちょっとお手紙、いいですか？
So, would you like to hear the letter?
はい。
Yes!
ということで、あ、これ2枚目だぞ。うぇ、ちょっと、ちょっと！
So— Ah, this is the second page! Whoa, wait, wait!
1枚目をだしてくれ！
Bring out the first page!
はい、出るかな？大丈夫かな？
Okay, will it appear? Will it be okay?
はい、じゃあ読んでいきますよ、出るかな？
Okay, then I'll read it. Will it come out?
はい、ということで、お手紙を読んでいきたいと思います。
Okay, then I'd like to read the letter.
いつも応援してくれる君へ。
To you who always supports me,
今日は祭りの誕生日です。
today is Matsuri's birthday.
お祝いしに来てくれてありがとう。祭りは本当に幸せ者です。
Thank you for coming to celebrate. Matsuri is truly a blessed person.
っていうこの書き出し方、実は去年の誕生日にも全く同じ文章でやりました。
This opening... actually, I used the exact same text for last year's birthday.
なんとね、
You see,
2回目ですね！祭りがデビューしてもう、なんと3回目…1回目はツイキャスで、2回目3回目がYouTubeでやってるんですけども、
it's the second time! Matsuri's 3rd birthday since debut... The 1st was on TwitCasting, and the 2nd and 3rd are on YouTube,
誕生日でございます。去年も一昨年もね、たくさんのファンの人たちにお祝いをしてもらいました。
but it's my birthday! Last year and the year before, I received celebrations from many fans.
でも今年はもっともっともっとたくさんの祭リス、そして大好きな後輩、仲間たちにコメント欄にもいますね、お祝いしてもらえて祭りはなんて幸せ者なんだろうって、心の底から思います。
But this year, receiving celebrations from even more Matsurisu, my beloved juniors and peers—I see them in the chat too—makes Matsuri truly feel from the bottom of her heart how blessed she is.
今年もお祝いしてくれたそこそこの君、もちろん来年の今日も、さ来年の今日も、お祝いしてくれるよね？答えはYESしか受け付けていません！
To you over there who celebrated with me this year: Of course you'll celebrate with me next year and the year after that, right? I only accept "YES" as an answer!
デビューして早2年、ずっと変わらず自由に、そして頑固に活動を続けてきて、前から見てくれてる祭リスも、最近知ってくれた祭リスの君も、本当に祭りの心の支えです。
It's been 2 years since my debut, continuing to work freely and stubbornly as ever. Both the Matsurisu who have watched me from the start and you Matsurisu who discovered me recently are truly Matsuri's emotional support.
正直に話すと、何度かやめようって思ったこともありました。でも、つらいときに祭リスから好きだよって言葉をね、エゴサとかコメントとかからもらって、支えられて、もう少し頑張ろう、もう少し頑張ろうってやってたら、3回目の誕生日である今日が来ました。
To be honest, there were times when I thought about quitting. But when things were tough, getting words of love from Matsurisu through egosnaps and comments supported me. Thinking "I'll try a little harder, a little harder," today, my 3rd birthday, has arrived.
きっとこれからもね、もうちょっと、あ、そうちょっと頑張ろうを続けていくんだろうなって思います。
I'm sure from now on, too, I'll continue thinking "Let's work a little harder, oh, let's work a little harder" and keep going.
だから、祭りにもう少し頑張ろうって思わせてくれた君だから、祭りももう少しだけおそうかなって、長く長く思わせることのできるアイドルになります。
Therefore, because it's you who made Matsuri want to try a little harder, Matsuri will become an idol who can make you think "I want to support her just a bit longer" for a long, long time.
あと、ずっと夢は変わらずお姫様にも絶対絶対なって見せるから、去年よりもね近づいている気もするので、なので、祭りがお姫様になるその日まで離れずに見守ってくださると嬉しいです。
Also, my dream remains unchanged: I will definitely, definitely become a princess. I feel I'm getting closer than last year, so I'd be happy if you stayed close and watched over me until the day Matsuri becomes a princess.
後悔はさせませんよ！
I won't let you regret it!
改めて、今日は本当にありがとう。いつも言ってるけどいつ言ってる以上の大好きを君に。夏色まつりより。
Once again, thank you so much today. As I always say, but with more love than ever: to you. From Natsuiro Matsuri.
はい、お手紙でした！
Yes, that was the letter!
どうだったかな？もう祭りの素直な気持ちをね、あの昨日せっせこ書きましたよ、はい。
How was it? I hurriedly wrote down Matsuri's honest feelings yesterday, yes.
なんか恥ずかしいですね。というところで、皆さん本当に、あの、ありがとうございます、今日集まってくれて、あの、ホロライブメンバーもね、そして今日来てくれたルーナも本当にありがとう、大好きでございます。
It's kind of embarrassing. Anyway, thank you all so much for gathering today—Hololive members and Luna who came today as well, thank you so much, I love you all.
はい、ということでね、こんな話をしていますが、ここからは、告知タ——イ——ム——イェーーイ！はい！
Yes, so while we're talking about this, from here on is... Announcement tiiiiime! Yay! Yes!
祭ちゃん、なんと告知がめちゃめちゃあるので、ちょっと駆け足で行きたいと思います。
Matsuri-chan has so many announcements, so I'd like to go through them quickly.
まずは、もう情報が出ているものから行きましょうか。みんないつもありがと、ありがとねこちらもう。ありがと、誕生日おめでと、ありがとね。それではまず1つ目から行きますよ！こちらです。
First, let's go with the information already released. Everyone, thank you as always, thanks here too. Thanks, happy birthday, thanks. So, let's start with the first one! Here it is.
どーも！あ、前だね。どーも！えー7月22日水曜日21時よりもう始まっております、楽天にて発売決定しております！ホロライブ×宮田のヤングドーナツコラボがありますよ！
Hello! Ah, it's in front. Hello! Um, starting July 22nd (Wednesday) at 21:00, already underway, it's been decided to release on Rakuten! There's a Hololive x Miyata's Young Donuts collaboration!
はい、あの、全5種類の、あの、限定カードもついてくるのでね、ぜひねコンプリートセット、5つカードコンプリートセットになるので、皆さんぜひ、あの、5種類限定なのでお早めにお願いいたします！
Yes, all 5 types of limited cards are included, so please get the complete set—since there are 5 card complete sets, everyone, since it's limited to 5 types, please order early!
もうね、めちゃめちゃ嬉しい、祭りヤングドーナツ大好きだからね、ぜひ皆さんお願いします！
I'm so happy, I love Matsuri Young Donuts, so everyone please check it out!
はい、じゃあ続いて、まあこれはもう匂わせがもうすごかったので、分かると思うんですけど、こちら行きましょう！
Yes, next—well, the hints for this were so huge you probably already know, let's go to this one!
おっどーも！
Hello there!
はい、新Live2Dお披露目ということで、
Yes, announcing the new Live2D debuts,
7月の28日より、
starting July 28th,
ホロライブの新Live2Dのお披露目会が順次行われていきます。
Hololive's new Live2D debut streams will be held in order.
まず7月28日は、なんとリレーでございます！
First, July 28th will feature a relay stream!
7月28日21時から紫咲シオン、
July 28th at 21:00, Murasaki Shion,
7月28日22時から白上フブキ、
July 28th at 22:00, Shirakami Fubuki,
7月28日23時から私夏色まつりとね、
and July 28th at 23:00, me, Natsuiro Matsuri,
もう怒涛の、怒涛の新Live2Dお披露目会でございますが、
a non-stop, consecutive series of new Live2D debuts!
まつり見たけど、マジで可愛い！全員ね、マジで可愛いから
I saw them, and they're seriously cute! Everyone is seriously so cute,
忘れずにね、おしおチェックしていきましょう。
so don't forget to check them out.
まずは3人からですよ、よろしくお願いします！
Starting with these three, so please look forward to it!
じゃあ続いて、ここからは初出しの情報となります！こちら、どどーん！
Next up, we have some brand-new information! Here it is, ta-da!
はい、夏色まつり参戦！
Yes! Natsuiro Matsuri is joining!
うつろにっきというアプリゲームに、キャラクターCVとして出演させていただくことになりました。
I'll be appearing as a character voice in the app game "Utsuro Nikki".
過去にはね、あの朝のルネとかロボ子先輩とかも出ております、うつろにっきアプリゲームでございますね。
Previously, Asano Ruri and Roboco-senpai have also appeared in the "Utsuro Nikki" app game.
まつりがキャラクターCVを務めさせていただきますよ！ヤンデレホラー系のね、やつ、ヤンデレをまつりちゃんがやるのかというところでございますが、
I'll be serving as the character voice! It's a yandere horror-style game, and you might wonder if Matsuri-chan can pull off a yandere role,
こちらもね、あの、出たらね、また告知をTwitterなどでさせていただきますので、よろしくお願いします！
but once it's released, I'll announce it on Twitter, so please look forward to it!
声優になっちゃうよ、まつりちゃん！
Matsuri-chan's becoming a voice actress!
はい、じゃあ続いてまいりましょう！
Alright, let's move on!
これもびっくりしますよ！こちら、どどーん！
This will surprise you too! Here it is, ta-da!
夏色まつりねんどろいどフィギュア化決定！ありがとうございます！
Natsuiro Matsuri Nendoroid figure adaptation confirmed! Thank you so much!
まつりちゃんがなんとねんどろいどになって登場でございます！
Matsuri-chan is appearing as a Nendoroid!
カミングスーンということで詳しい情報はまだ出ていないんですが、こちらのね、あのねんどろいど
It's coming soon, so detailed info isn't out yet, but this Nendoroid...
出る際にはまた告知しますので、ぜひぜひご購入いただけたら嬉しいなと
I'll announce it when it comes out, so I'd be so happy if you'd purchase one.
思います。めちゃめちゃ可愛いでしょ？可愛くなっているのでよろしくお願いしますね！
It's super cute, right? It's turning out so cute, so please look forward to it!
はい、じゃあ続いては、こちらでございます！どどーん！
Alright, next up is this! Ta-da!
情報出ておりますが、ノンストップストーリーのBlu-ray発売記念でですね、
Information is out, but to celebrate the release of the "Non-Stop Story" Blu-ray,
トレーラー映像が都市3箇所にて、該当ビジョンにて放映決定しております。
trailer footage has been decided to be broadcast on screens in three cities!
放映期間は7月の18日土曜日から24日金曜日です。もうね、すでに放映されておりますよ。
The broadcasting period is from Saturday, July 18th to Friday, July 24th. It's already being broadcast!
東京ではユニカビジョン、おのね、MXビジョンなどが計7箇所で放映されておりまして、
In Tokyo, Unica Vision, Oono MX Vision, etc., are broadcasting at a total of 7 locations.
名古屋ではライトニングウェーブナギさんにて放映しております。
In Nagoya, it's being broadcast at Lightning Wave Nagi.
大阪はトンボリステーション、新サイバシオーパビジョンにて放映されております。
In Osaka, it's being broadcast at Tombori Station and Shinsaibashi Opa Vision.
さらにノンストップストーリー発売記念特別トレーラー約2分半の放映も決定しております。
Furthermore, a special trailer of about 2 and a half minutes for the "Non-Stop Story" Blu-ray release has also been decided to air.
日時が7月の23日、間違えました、23日の木曜日、明日ですね。
The date and time is July 23rd—my mistake, Thursday the 23rd, tomorrow—around 19:00.
19時頃に東京ユニカビジョンさん、名古屋ライトニングウェーブナギさん、大阪トンボリステーション、新サイバシオーパビジョンさんにて、7月の23日明日19時頃に放映するのでぜひ皆さん見てください。
At around 19:00 at Tokyo Unica Vision, Nagoya Lightning Wave Nagi, Osaka Tombori Station, and Shinsaibashi Opa Vision, it will air tomorrow around 19:00, so everyone please check it out.
このほか7月23日同時刻にホロライブのニコニコファンクラブ会員限定コンテストでございます。
In addition, at the same time on July 23rd, there is a Hololive Niconico Fan Club member-limited contest.
でもですね、同映像を、同じ映像を放映予定なので、ぜひニコニコファンクラブ入ってくださってる方はチェックしてください。
But since the same footage is scheduled to be broadcast, those who have joined the Niconico Fan Club, please check it out.
Blu-ray予約が7月の23日明日までです。
Blu-ray reservations are until tomorrow, July 23rd.
ただし、現在予約分の在庫切れにより、追加生産分の受付を7月23日まで、明日まで実施中なので、まだ予約してなかったっていう人はチェックしてみてください。
However, due to current reservation stock running out, we are currently accepting additional production orders until tomorrow, July 23rd, so if you haven't reserved yet, please check it out.
こちらは9月の初旬から中頃にお届け予定となります。
These are scheduled to be delivered from early to mid-September.
一般販売は7月の24日から、こちらの商品は7月末から8月上旬頃のお届けとなります。
General sales start on July 24th, and these items will be delivered around late July to early August.
ただし在庫に限りがありますので、何卒ご容赦くださいましてよろしくお願いします！
However, stock is limited, so please understand and thank you!
ちょっと日本語おかしくなっちゃいましたけど、
My Japanese got a bit weird there,
ドーナツが完売！ありがとうございます！9分で5000個売り切れ！ありがとうございます！
but the donuts sold out! Thank you! 5,000 pieces sold out in 9 minutes! Thank you so much!
マジで早い！ありがとうございます！
Seriously so fast! Thank you!
そしてですね、19時から放送がありました、トワッチについての新情報です！こちら、どどーん！
And then, we have new information regarding Towa-chi, which was broadcast from 19:00! Here it is, ta-da!
常闇トワ3Dお披露目会！
Tokoyami Towa's 3D debut stream!
7月の26日、もうすぐ日曜日の夜20時から！
July 26th, coming up this Sunday night at 20:00!
ハッシュタグは常闇トワ3Dでみなさんたくさんもうすでにね、
The hashtag is #TokoyamiTowa3D. I'm sure many of you have already tweeted about it,
ツイートしてる方もいらっしゃると思いますが、ツイートしてトレンドに入れてあげてくださいお願いします！絶対見てねみんな！楽しみでございますね。
but please tweet it and get it into the trends, please! Everyone, definitely watch it! I'm so looking forward to it.
はい、そして、まつりすのそこなきみ、お待たせしました！こちらです、どどーん！
And finally, Matsurisu, you've been waiting for this! Here it is, ta-da!
誕生日記念ボイス2020、7月22日販売開始！
2020 Birthday Commemorative Voice pack, on sale starting July 22nd!
はい、開始でございます！
Yes, it's starting!
夏色まつりの誕生日記念ボイスが7月の22日今日！
Natsuiro Matsuri's birthday voice pack is available today, July 22nd!
配信終了時に販売開始いたします！
Sales will begin as soon as this stream ends!
販売ページのURLは概要欄の方に記載してあるそうです。
The sales page URL is listed in the video description.
あの配信終了後にね、あの記載されるそうなので、ローの画面をロードロードしてくださいね。
Since it'll be posted after the stream, please refresh your browser then.
あとまつりの方でもね、Twitterでつぶやかせていただきたいと思います。
I'll also post about it on Twitter from my account.
南村はっきー先生のかき下ろしA5アクリルパネルも販売しますのでよろしくお願いします。
An A5 acrylic panel illustrated by Minamimura Hachii-sensei will also be on sale!
これね、記念品付き全部セットっていうのがあってね、それをね買うとね付いてきます。
There's an all-in-one set with commemorative goods that comes with it.
あとね、まつりの直筆サイン入り手紙風メッセージカードも付いてきますのでね。
Plus, it comes with a message card featuring Matsuri's hand-written signature!
ちなみにあの、直筆サインももう1枚1枚丁寧に書いていきますのでよろしくお願いします。
By the way, I'll be carefully signing every single autograph card by hand.
メッセージカードはね、まつりが実際に書いたものをしゅしゅしゅって印刷してもらえます。
The message cards will be printed from originals I actually wrote myself!
はい、えーと、という感じございますね！
Yep! So that's basically it!
はい、いっぱい喋った！いっぱいいっぱい喋りましたけども、みなさんこんな感じで。
Whew, I talked so much! I talked quite a bit, but everyone...
まあおさらいするとヤングドーナツ、もう売り切れちゃったけどね、もう先着ありがとうございます！販売オンレ。
To recap, the Young Donuts sold out already—thank you for the early purchases!
そして、えっと7月の28日の21時からね、リレーでライブ2Dの新お披露目があるよっていうのと、アプリゲームのキャラクターCVになるよっていうのと、ねんどろいどが発売するよっていうのと、NSSのなんか映像があるよっていうのと、とわちの3Dと記念ボイスがあるよっていうことですね。
Also, July 28th at 9 PM brings Live2D, app characters, Nendoroids, and more!
はい、ということで、え、長々と告知させていただきましたけど、みなさん頭に入りましたか？
Phew, so I made quite a few announcements—did you get all that?
頭に入ったかな？
Did it sink in?
ということで、今日はね本当にありがとうございます誕生日改めて。
So yeah, thank you truly so much for my birthday once again!
はい、ということで、それではここで最後の歌を歌って終わりたいと思います。あ、最後まで見てね、何があるかは内緒ですけど。
Alright, I'd like to wrap things up by singing one last song.
それでは聴いてください。
Now then, please listen.
夢見る空へ
"To the Dreaming Sky"
重ねた手はギュッと離さずに 行くよ！
Without letting go of our intertwined hands, let's go!
夢見る空へ！
To the dreaming sky!
今日は本当にありがとう！愛してるよ！
Thank you so much today! I love you!
窓越しに見上げた とても小さな空
The tiny sky I looked up at through the window...
ここで出会えたのは 数え切れないキセキ
meeting here is an endless miracle.
繰り返した一歩が キラメキをつないで
Every repeated step connects our sparkle,
星のような笑顔を見せていた
showing smiles like the stars.
day by day みんなの声がチカラになる
Day by day, everyone's voice becomes my strength.
stage by stage ここでそれぞれ目指すもの
Stage by stage, what each of us aims for here,
それぞれ描くもの それぞれ願った夢へ
what each depicts, toward the dream each wished for.
重ねた手はギュッと離さずに
Without letting go of our intertwined hands,
ひとり（ひとり）違う（色で）描き出すトキメキ
each drawing out our excitement in different colors.
振り向くことなくまっすぐに発進進行
Moving straight ahead without looking back, ignition and launch!
行くよ！（行こう！）夢見る空へ
Let's go! To the dreaming sky!
笑い合ったことや 月並みな言い訳
Laughing together and ordinary excuses,
想い出いっぱいなのに
even though our memories are overflowing,
あっという間の日々 上書きじゃなくて名前付けて保存
these fleeting days—save them with a name, not just overwriting!
どれも全部大切に握りしめる
I'll hold onto every single one dearly.
one for all “みんなのため”がチカラになる
One for all, "for everyone" becomes my strength.
all for all 今日も賑やかすぎるくらい
All for all, today is lively enough
笑顔がもたまらない 想いは膨らんでいく
that my smiles won't stop, and my feelings keep expanding.
重ねた今ギュッと噛み締めた
Savoring this intertwined present tightly,
ひとり（ひとり）違う（声で）歌声は広がる
our singing voices spread, each with a different voice.
風を感じたらまっすぐに発進進行
Feeling the wind, heading straight ahead, ignition and launch!
行くよ！夢見る空へ
Let's go! To the dreaming sky!
吹き抜ける風を
Chasing the sweeping wind,
追い越して行こう
let's go beyond it!
譲れない気持ちが
Unyielding feelings
羽根をくれたの
gave me wings.
どんな未来にする?
What kind of future shall we make?
声にしたなら
If we put it into words,
重なるドキドキ
our overlapping heartbeats
想うままに駆け出そう
will run forth just as we imagine!
祭りはこれからもずっとずっと頑張っていくので、絶対に今回はさせないので
Matsuri is going to keep working harder and harder, so I definitely won't let you...
ついてきてください！
Please follow along with me!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you very much!
重ねた手はギュッと離さずに
Holding our joined hands tight without letting go,
ひとりひとり違う未来を描き出す
each of us portrays a different future.
出会ったすべてにありがとう
Thank you for everything we met,
奇跡起こし続けてずっとそばにいるよ
working miracles, I'll always be by your side!
行くよ 夢見る空へ
Here we go, to the sky of our dreams!
ありがとう！愛してるぞー！
Thank you! I love you guys!
来年も一緒に過ごそうね。
Let's spend next year together too, okay?
約束！
Promise!
夏色まつり誕生日祭！重大告知
[Natsuiro Matsuri Birthday Festival! Major Announcement]